<article id="0000008" published-at="2017-11-15" title="Texas State University suspends Greek life after student death"><p>Nov.
 15 (UPI) ? Texas State University has suspended all Greek life activity on campus after a pledge died after attending an even
t hosted by a university fraternity.</p>
<p>Police officers found Matthew Ellis, a 20-year-old Phi Kappa Psi pledge, dead on Monday after they responded to an off-camp
us call. Ellis attended a Greek life event on Sunday hosted by fraternity members, but it is unclear if the event was hosted b
y one fraternity or multiple fraternities.</p>
<p>Although an autopsy has been ordered, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/storyline/hazing-in-america/texas-state-university-suspends-greek-life-activity-after-frat-pledge-n820946" type="external">a preliminary investigation suggested alcohol poisoning</a> as a factor in the student?s death.</p>
<p>Phi Kappa Psi Executive Director Mark Guidi said that the organization is ?heartbroken.?</p>
<p>?Our thoughts and prayers are with his family, friends and the entire TSU student body during this difficult time,? Giudi said.</p>
<p>Texas State University President Denise M. Trauth <a href="http://www.txstate.edu/news/news_releases/news_archive/2017/November-2017/Greeks111417.html" type="external">released a statement</a> announcing the suspension of Greek life activity on campus.</p>
<p>?I am deeply saddened by the tragic death of one of our students who attended an off-campus social event on Sunday evening hosted by members of a university fraternity,? Trauth said.</p>
<p>?As a result of this tragedy, I have suspended activities of all Greek fraternity and sorority chapters at Texas State. These chapters are prohibited from holding new-member events, chapter meetings, social functions, and philanthropic activities until a thorough review of the Greek Affairs system is completed.?</p>
<p>Trauth also said Vice President for Student Affairs Dr. Joanne Smith would ?immediately initiate this review? and would ?propose recommendations? for the Greek chapters to show their ?commitment to the core values of Texas State.?</p>
<p>?It is imperative that our entire university community develop a culture that places the highest priority on the safety of its students, faculty, and staff.?</p></article>
