<article id="0000001" published-at="2017-09-10" title="After DeVos Announced Plans To Reexamine Title IX, Texas Attorney Tweet
s He Would 'Be Ok If [She] Was Sexually Assaulted'"><p>When explaining her decision to reevaluate Title IX guidelines as they
pertain to sexual assault on college campuses, Secretary of Education Betsy DeVos <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-new
s/betsy-devos-overhaul-obama-era-guidance-campus-sex-assault-n799471" type="external">said</a>: ?Every survivor of sexual misc
onduct must be taken seriously. Every student accused of sexual misconduct must know that guilt is not predetermined.?</p>
<p>The Obama administration?s changes to Title IX have been <a href="" type="internal">criticized</a> for, among other things,
 substantially lowering the burden of proof as it pertains to sexual assault, as well as denying elements of due process to th
e accused.</p>
<p>However, many progressives are lashing out at DeVos because they hate her, and also rape culture and stuff.</p>
<p>Perhaps the most grotesque attack came when Rob Ranco, a Texas attorney, tweeted Friday that ?I'm not wishing for it ? but
I'd be ok if #BetsyDevos was sexually assaulted. #Sexual Assault #TitleIX.?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2017/sep/9/rob-ranco-texas-lawyer-says-he-would-be-ok-if-bets/" type="external
">The Washington Times</a> reports that in several other tweets (condensed for this publication), Ranco wrote: ?Perhaps Betsy
doesn?t understand how horrible rape is. She?s made the world more dangerous for my daughters. I need her to understand,? and
?Make the world more dangerous for my daughters ? intentionally ? and your well being is not my concern. Full stop.?</p>
<p>Ranco's additional tweets don't make his first one any less vile.</p>
<p>In the wake of the overwhelming negative response, Ranco locked his Twitter profile, then <a href="https://www.redstate.com
/brandon_morse/2017/09/09/cowardly-austin-lawyer-wished-sexual-assault-betsy-devos-locked-twitter-account/" type="external">de
leted</a> it.</p>
<p>Many on social media are calling for the attorney to be fired from The Carlson Law Firm, where he is a partner, or even dis
barred:</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/PrisonPlanet" type="external">@PrisonPlanet</a> I'm wishing for it... but I'd be ok if <a href
="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RobRanco?src=hash" type="external">#RobRanco</a> was disbarred.</p>
<p>As of this publication, the law firm?s Twitter account has also been locked, though Ranco is still listed on the official w
ebsite?s ? <a href="https://www.carlsonattorneys.com/team-member/robert-ranco/" type="external">Team</a>? section.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.change.org/p/texas-bar-association-removal-of-law-license-for-misogynistic-tweet-of-approval-of-sexu
al-assault-on-woman?recruiter=778517695&amp;amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=shar
e_twitter_responsive" type="external">petition</a>, which currently boasts nearly 2,200 signatures, has also been started in a
n effort to get the attorney disbarred.</p></article>
